先生们  我想我找到了一个
Gentlemen, I think I've come up with a fun way
让年轻人对科学感兴趣的办法了
to get young people interested in science.
物理疯狂填词游戏
Physics Mad-Libs.
一篇文章中若干单词空缺  并指定填入单词的词性
其他人或自己可以随机说出一些固定词性的单词
-给我个数字  -五
- Now, give me a number.  - Five.
再给我一个无理数
And an irrational constant.
E[欧拉数]
"E."
再来一个搞笑的希腊字母
And a funny Greek letter.
γ[希腊语的第三个字母]
Gamma.
我说了要搞笑的
I said funny.
-那Y[希腊语第二十个字母]呢  -不错
- Upsilon?  - Good one.
再给我一个电荷
And an electrical charge.
正电荷
Positive.
棒极了
Perfect.
好了  听好了
Okay. Get this.
"琼斯教授在讨论会上宣布
"Professor Jones told the symposium
他找到了计算介子质量的新办法
he had a new method for calculating the mass of a muon.
E到Y极限的五倍..."
Five times the limit of  'E' to the upsilon as..."
好吧  不笑了  不笑了
Okay. No, no.
我重说一遍
I'll start over.
"琼斯教授"
"Professor..."
打从莱纳德犯了个乘法错误后
I haven't seen him laugh that hard
我还真没见他狂笑成这样过
since the day Leonard made that multiplication error.
天啊  那个乘法错误
Oh, Oh, Lord, that multiplication error!
他以为自己有进位
He thought he carried the one.
其实根本没有
But he didn't.
一点也不好笑
It's not funny.
那篇错误的论文还被发表了
That mistake got published.
别说了  我笑得都快尿裤子了
Stop! I'm going to wet myself!
伙计们  伙计们  赛博特校长朝咱们走过来了
Hey, guys, guys, President Siebert is headed this way.
-他来干嘛  -看样子不太爽
- I wonder what he wants.  - Doesn't look happy,
所以我猜应该是来找谢尔顿的
so I'm guessing he wants to talk to Sheldon.
库珀博士
Dr. Cooper?
我就说嘛
Told ya.
赛博特校长
Oh, President Siebert,
我猜您是来回复我在您办公室旁放置的
I assume you'd like to respond to one of the suggestions
建议箱里的其中一条建议吧
I put in the box by your office.
不是  你别再到处给我装建议箱了
No, and stop installing suggestion boxes everywhere.
您不喜欢书面建议
You don't like written suggestions.
您也不喜欢咱们一起上厕所时
You don't like when I give them to you
我给您的口头建议
while we're urinating in the men's room.
要不是我对您有所了解  我会以为您也是
If I didn't know you any better, I'd say that you're one of those
那种固执己见  不肯采纳他人意见的老古板呢
stubborn people who are not open to suggestions.
库珀博士  物理学部门的主席告诉我
Dr. Cooper, the physics department chair tells me
你不肯休假
you're refusing to take your vacation.
我不需要休假
I don't need a vacation.
你有休假的义务
You're obligated to take one.
而且我想告诉你  在你没经过我同意
And I'd also like you to know the most-often received
就擅自给我装的建议箱里  收到的最多的建议就是
suggestion in my suggestion box you installed without asking me
"能不能让库珀博士去休假呀"
is "Can Dr. Cooper take a vacation?"
好吧  问题解决  那咱们就周一见咯
Okay, settled, then. I'll see y'all of you Monday,
除了你
except for you.
但如果我不来上班
But if I don't come into work,
那我自己要去干嘛
what am I supposed to do with myself?
看书  休息  旅游
Read, rest, travel.
我听说这个季节去阿富汗不错
I hear Afghanistan is nice this time of year.
是说反话吗
Sarcasm?
不是  你真该去一趟
No. You should go.
* 今夜将是个美好的夜晚 *
* That tonight's gonna be a good night *
* And tonight's gonna be a good night *
* 今夜将是个美好得不得了的夜晚 *
* And tonight's gonna be a good, good night *
* 就是今夜 *
* Tonight's the night, uh, uh *
* 齐来狂欢 *
* Let's live it up, uh *
* 钱早备好  尽情挥霍...*
* I got my money, let's spend it up... *
上帝啊
Good Lord!
你别跟猫叫春一样行不
Would you stop that caterwauling!
你在这里干嘛
What the hell are you doing?!
听你蹂躏我的耳朵到出血呀
Bleeding from my ears.
你藏在我车后座上干嘛
What are you doing hiding back there?
我要偷溜去上班
I'm sneaking into work.
如果大学门口的保安问你
Now, if the guard at the university asks
毯子下面藏着什么
what's under the blanket,
你就跟他说是捕龙虾的装置
you tell him it's some lobster traps.
-捕龙虾的装置  -没错
- Lobster traps?  - Yes.
维尔玛和史酷比就是这样
That's how Velma and Scooby
把主人毛毛偷运进那个老灯塔里的
smuggled Shaggy into the old lighthouse.
你进到学校里面以后怎么办呢
What are you going to do when you get to the university?
人们肯定会认出你的
People are going to recognize you.
有可能吗  莱纳德
Will they, Leonard?
好吧  乖乖藏回毯子底下
Fine. Just get back under your blanket,
我会载你过去的
and I'll drive you there.
不许再唱歌了
And no more singing.
好吧
Fine.
我手机有导航
I have GPS on my phone.
我知道你掉头了
I know you turned around.
我真高兴你说服了霍华德
I'm so glad you talked Howard
不要用克林贡语来写你们的结婚喜帖
out of having your wedding invitations in Klingon.
翻过来看背面
Turn it over.
希望我的亲戚会以为这是希伯来语
I'm hoping my relatives think it's Hebrew.
今天终于来了
This is really happening.
我要当伴娘了
I'm gonna be a maid of honor.
我将穿着一条漂亮的裙子  走过教堂的走廊
I'm gonna wear a beautiful dress and walk down that aisle
然后迎来我的大日子
and, finally, I will have my special day.
你是说我的大日子吧
You mean my special day?
某人的新娘头纱得要加大码的
They're gonna need an extra-large veil for somebody's head.
如果我真的能结成婚
If I ever actually ever get married.
为什么结不成
Why wouldn't you?
因为我爸呗
My dad...
我挣得钱比华仔多
'Cause I make a lot more money than Howie,
所以我老爸逼我签订一个婚前协议
he's putting a lot of pressure on me to get a prenup.
这可不妙
Ouch.
是啊  华仔会抓狂的
Yeah. Howie's gonna freak out.
来自父母的压力还真是可怕
Parental pressure can be daunting.
记得我以前因为不愿刮腿毛而跟我妈吵架
I remember the battle with my mother about shaving my legs.
去年我终于举腿投降  让她把我刮了
Last year, I finally gave in and let her do it.
我真不知道该怎么跟他说这件事
I just don't know how I'm gonna break it to him.
我坚信向男人宣布坏消息的最好时机
You know, I'm a big believer in breaking bad news
就是跟他在床上的时候
to a guy when you're in bed with him.
我就是这么告诉我高中男友
That's how I told my high school boyfriend
我跟他哥上床的事情
I slept with his brother.
然后场景不变  再把主角换成他哥
That's how I told his brother the same thing.
我不知道  可我不想用性来操纵他
I don't know, I don't want to manipulate him with sex.
亲爱的  这才是性的用处所在
Oh, sweetie, that's what sex is for.
其实婚姻和金钱的联系  早在过去便如此
You know, the connection between marriage and money is nothing new.
"结婚"一词在过去就是指
In fact, the term "wed" referred to the money and livestock
新郎付给岳父的金钱和牲畜
that the groom paid the bride's father.
比如
For example,
如果你长得标致
you're adorable,
聪明伶俐又会挣钱
intelligent and a good earner.
保守地说  你也能得到
I could conservatively see you going for
至少两头牛和一只鹅
at least two oxen and a goose.
而你  绝对能收到一头独角兽
You would fetch a unicorn.
谢尔顿  有很多度假胜地你可以去
Sheldon, there are a million great vacations you could take.
夏威夷怎么样
What about Hawaii?
夏威夷就是昔日坐落在活火山上的麻风病人隔离区
Hawaii is a former leper colony on top of an active volcano
《迷失》的烂结局也是在那里拍的
where the disappointing ending to Lost was filmed.
真他妈感谢你  夏威夷
Mahalo for nothing, Hawaii.
那佛罗里达呢
How about Florida?
那里有卡纳维拉尔角
They got Cape Canaveral,
迪士尼乐园  我的艾达姨妈也在那
they got Disney, they got my Aunt Ida
她集了世界上最全的糖尿病患吃的糖果
and the world's largest collection of diabetic candy.
而且  你要是汗出得够多
Plus, if you get sweaty enough,
还可以用她的塑料膜沙发玩激流勇进
her plastic-covered furniture is like a flume ride.
小时候俺家去佛罗里达旅行过一次
My family took a trip to Florida when I was a child.
在沙滩上  一只海鸥偷了我一条热狗
A seagull stole a hot dog from me on the beach.
我就知道这儿不欢迎我
I got the message.
我要是能放一周假
You know, if I had a week off, I'd go back
我会再去沙漠温泉酒店
to the Two Bunch Palms Resort and Spa in the desert.
告诉你们  让特雷弗给你按摩一小时
I tell you, an hour on the massage table with Trevor,
你会酥软到觉得自己生来就没骨头
and you'll feel like you were born without bones.
我估计受不了一个男的给我按摩
I don't think I could ever let a guy give me a massage.
是吗  那昨晚你玩X-BOX的时候
Really? What was I doing to your neck last night
我在给你的脖子做什么
while you were playing X-Box?
感觉我就像生活在独裁之中
It's like I'm living in a dictatorship.
"你一定要去度假  你一定要开心
"You must take a vacation, you must have fun,
你一定要享受生活"
you must enjoy life."
你好像误解了独裁的意思吧
I don't think you have a good handle on dictatorships.
谢尔顿  每个人都需要休假
Sheldon, everybody takes vacations.
理查德·费曼以前也被逼着休假
One time they tried to make Richard Feynman take a vacation,
可他选择拓宽思维
but he chose instead to expand his mind
学一些新知识
and learn something new.
他去了朋友的生物实验室工作
He went to work in his friend's biology lab.
理查德·费曼是美国著名的物理学家
Richard Feynman was a famous American physicist,
曼哈顿工程  是第二次世界大战期间
盎格鲁国家秘密研发原子弹项目的代号
参与过曼哈顿工程
part of the Manhattan Project.
科学界的人都知道理查德·费曼是谁
Everyone in the world of science knows who Richard Feynman was.
你是现在才知道的吧
Now you do, too.
我想到了一个绝妙的主意
Oh! I have a brilliant idea.
艾米是生物学家  我可以去她的实验室工作
Amy's a biologist. I'll go work in her lab.
这不就是费曼的主意吗
Isn't that just Feynman's idea?
几秒钟前你还没听说过他
Ten seconds ago, you never heard of him.
现在就装起专家来了
Now you're an expert.
-这么巧  -这是要洗的衣服吗
- Hey, you. - Is that your laundry?
怎么才这么几件
You only have, like, six things in there.
我没有零钱了
Yeah, I didn't have any quarters,
所以一直偷偷把衣服塞到别人的衣服堆里
so I've been sneaking stuff into other people's loads all day.
如果我告诉你一件事
Hey, if I tell you something,
你能保证不告诉别人吗
will you promise not to tell anybody?
我说什么无所谓  反正你也会告诉我
It doesn't matter what I say, you're gonna tell me anyway.
什么  才没有这回事
What? That is not true.
伯纳黛特想签婚前协议
Bernadette wants a prenup.
这事过分了吧
Wow. That's rough.
这么说如果我成了著名影星
So you're saying if I became a famous movie star,
我们结婚的话  你不会签婚前协议吗
we got married, you wouldn't sign a prenup?
绝对不会
Absolutely not.
如果我要待在家里带孩子
If I'm gonna be stuck at home with the kids
而你在出外景
while you're on location
跟瑞安·高斯林玩偷吃
cheating on me with Ryan Gosling...
那莱纳德就不是这么好打发的了
then Leonard gots to get paid.
你想过我们结婚吗
So, you think about us getting married?
我想的东西可多了
I think about a lot of things.
我会想我们结婚
I think about us getting married,
我也会想我们分手
I think about us breaking up.
有时  我还想
Once in a while, I think about
自己上个月在停车场
how I didn't leave a note on that Mercedes
撞了人家的奔驰没留字条
I dinged in the parking lot last month,
不过喝杯酒就抛到九霄云外了
but then I have a glass of wine and it passes.
随你怎么说笑  但你还是想了
Joke all you want, but you think about it.
告诉你一件事
Well, tell you one thing,
我要是真要结婚了  绝对不用克林贡语写喜帖
if I ever do get married, no Klingon invitations.
祝你能用这态度去抓住男人的心
Good luck catching a man with that attitude.
哎哟喂
Boy, oh, boy!
这次度假有了个美好的开端
This vacation is off to a wonderful start.
甲醛的气味
The smell of formaldehyde...
离心机的嗡嗡声
the whir of the centrifuge,
被送去解剖的实验室动物
the distant chatter of lab animals
那渐渐远去的叫喊声
being dispatched for dissection.
我觉得自己的担心在慢慢消逝
Mm, I can already feel my cares just melting away.
我很高兴能和自己的男朋友公事
I'm excited to work with my boyfriend.
肯定很浪漫
It's gonna be romantic.
真会扫兴
Way to kill the mood.
别这么说  谢尔顿
Come on, Sheldon.
我们可以像玛丽·居里和她丈夫皮埃尔那样
We can be like Marie Curie and her husband, Pierre,
他们日夜并肩工作
who spent their days working side by side,
沐浴在爱和镭的光辉下
bathed in the glow of their love and the radium
那玩意儿最终还要了她的命
that ultimately killed her.
《美女与野兽》弱爆了
Screw Beauty and the Beast;
这才是迪士尼应该拍的爱情故事
that's the love story Disney should tell.
好吧  我们从什么开始呢
Okay, what do we start with?
要不拼接一些基因  克隆一只羊
Maybe splicing some genes, clone a sheep,
或者在一只老鼠背上植个人耳
perhaps grow a human ear on a mouse's back?
哈哈  我是个怪胎
Ha-ha, I'm a freak!
我准备做一些脑干组织的实验
Oh, I'm gonna be doing some brain stem histology
你可以用那块海绵
while you put yourself on the business end
洗那些烧杯
of a sponge and wash those beakers.
洗烧杯
Wash those bea...
我明白了  欺负新来的是吧
Oh, I get it, a little hazing for the new fella.
我还得眼睛睁大点
Yeah, I'd better keep an eye out for, what,
小心显微镜上有鞋油
shoe polish on the microscope,
烤芝士三明治里有疯牛病菌  是吧
or mad cow disease in my grilled cheese sandwich?
不是  我真的要用干净的烧杯
No, I just need those beakers washed.
小兔子乖乖  赶紧干活了
Hippity-hop, quick like a bunny.
拜托  大名鼎鼎的谢尔顿博士在你实验室呢
Wha...? Excuse me, you have Dr. Sheldon Cooper in your lab.
你就让他做洗碗的工作啊
You're gonna make him do the dishes?
那不等于叫绿巨人
That's like asking the Incredible Hulk
去开泡菜罐头嘛
to open a pickle jar.
谢尔顿  你从没在生物实验室工作过
Sheldon, you've never worked in a lab like this before.
你对生物领域毫无经验
You have no experience in the field of biology.
我对生物的经验可多了
I have plenty of experience in biology.
我1998年买了个电子宠物鸡
I bought a Tamagotchi in 1998.
瞧
And...
它还活着呢
it's still alive.
所以没问题了吧
Let's do this.
-霍华德呢  -招呼都懒得打吗
- Where's Howard? - No "Hi, Raj"?
也不问我今天过得怎么样
No "How are you, Raj?"
一开口就问另一个白人在哪儿
Just straight to "Where's the other white guy?"
抱歉
I'm sorry.
听着  我听说了点关于他的事
So, listen, I heard something about him.
你能保密吗
Can you keep it between us?
哎哟  八卦
Ooh, gossip.
我刚来这的时候  我以为你们美国人
When I first got here, I thought you Americans
真的只在冷水机旁说八卦呢
really gossiped around the water cooler.
所以我去那边转悠了大概一个月
So I hung out there for, like, a month,
但我唯一听到的八卦就是  有个诡异的家伙
but the only gossip I ever heard was about some creepy guy
总是围着冷水机瞎转悠
hanging out by the water cooler.
伯纳黛特想要签婚前协议
Bernadette wants to get a prenup.
这太丢脸了  他肯定会悲痛欲绝的
Oh, that's a shame-- he's gonna be devastated.
我对处理这种情况没有经验
I never know what to do in these situations.
我该给他点建议吗
Should I give him a heads-up?
我给你的建议就跟我看真人秀《单身汉》的一样
Hmm. I'm gonna give you the same advice
当那些男人拿着玫瑰不知送给谁时  我就会嚷
I yell at the TV when the Bachelor's handing out roses.
随心所愿
Follow your heart.
快瞧瞧
Check it out.
看这份超大米花糖
Look at the size of that Rice Krispie Treat!
价钱一样哦
Same price.
霍华德  我得告诉你点事
Hey, Howard, I need to tell you something.
我知道  结婚前不该吃这些
I know, it's not on my wedding diet.
我不在乎
I don't care.
听着
Uh, l-listen, I...
我听说伯纳黛特想要你签婚前协议
heard that Bernadette's thinking about asking you for a prenup.
婚前协议
A prenup?
你要怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我不知道
I... don't know.
随心所愿
Follow your heart.
其实  这也没什么
You know what, it's... not a big deal.
她赚的钱比我多
She makes more money than me.
她想要保护自己的经济利益
She wants to protect her financial interests.
这完全合理
It's completely reasonable.
很好  你这心态不错
Good. That's a healthy attitude.
其实  这对我们两个都好
Yeah, actually, it's good for both of us.
我也有要保护的财产
I have assets to protect, too.
是吗  比如呢
Like what?
我有些很珍贵的漫画书
I've got some rare comic books.
那辆卫士摩托的贷款也快还清了
The Vespa's almost paid off.
我和妈在西奈山优先订了一个双人墓
And Ma and I have a primo double cemetery plot at Mt. Sinai
就在那个演过《三人行》里罗柏先生的人旁边
right near the guy who played Mr. Roper on Three's Company.
罗柏先生死了吗
Mr. Roper's dead?!
你怎么能人家在毫无心理准备下说出来呢
You can't just spring that on a guy!
给
Here you go.
这件实验室里的玻璃器皿
This is now the only lab
可是独一无二  因为它们被个有双博士学位
with glassware washed by a man with two doctorates
和一张卡尔·萨根签过的禁止令的人洗过
and a restraining order signed by Carl Sagan.
有肥皂泡  重新洗
Soap spots. Wash 'em again.
胡说八道
Y... You're being ridiculous!
这些器皿彻底洗干净了
Those are perfectly clean.
谢尔顿  这个量杯盛过
Sheldon, this beaker used to contain cerebral spinal fluid
死于梅毒的大象的脑脊液
from an elephant that died of syphilis.
如果真的彻底干净了
If it's, in fact, perfectly clean,
你敢拿去倒水喝吗
drink from it.
生物学家好刻薄
Biologists are mean.
好了  这个任务可能有点超出了你的能力
All right, perhaps this task will be a little bit more up your alley.
我要你数清这些培养皿里的细菌孢子
I need you to count the bacteria spores on these petri dishes.
那个清洁剂有问题
There was something wrong with that detergent.
有好多泡泡
That was way too bubbly.
-我想是吧  -我准备写一封
- I'm sure it was. - I intend to write
措辞强力的投诉信给肥皂公司
that soap company a strongly worded letter.
好吧  不错  现在开始数吧
Yeah, good for you. Now, start counting.
知道这地方需要什么东西吗
You know what this place needs?
建议箱
A suggestion box.
三百六十六
366...
三百六十七
367...
怎么样了
How's it going?
你是说数数吗
How's counting going?
我还在上幼儿园的时候
When I was in kindergarten,
我在学校才艺展示上背了圆周率小数点后的一千位
I recited pi to a thousand places for the school talent show.
-我想这难不倒我  -很好
- I think I got this.  - Great.
我擦
Aw, nuts!
一
One...
这太可笑了
This is preposterous!
你一直让我做这些工作
I think you're giving me these tasks
因为你担心我要是做了有意义的工作
because you're afraid if you give me anything meaningful to do,
我就会超过你
I'll show you up.
真的吗  你就这么想的吗
Really? Is that what you think?
对  我就是这么想的
Yes, that's what I think.
而我这么超级聪明的人  这没准就是事实
And I'm super smart, so it's probably true.
我在神经生物学领域锻炼了12年
Hey, I've been training in the field of neurobiology for 12 years.
而你只来了3小时
You've been here for three hours,
其中1小时还花在厕所里了
and you've spent one of them in the bathroom.
不好意思  我没上过这里的厕所
I'm sorry! It takes me a while
总得花点时间来熟悉熟悉
to get things going on an unfamiliar toilet.
谢尔顿  我给你的都是最简单的工作
Sheldon, I've given you the simplest things to do,
你还一件都没有做对
and you haven't done one of them right.
也许是因为这些工作没有挑战
Maybe that's because I'm not being challenged.
就和爱因斯坦数学不及格一样
It's the same reason Einstein failed math.
也许数学对他来说泡泡[0]太多了
Maybe the math was too bubbly for him.
你觉得切割大脑需要技术含量吗
You think you're doing science by cutting up that brain?
这和在三明治店做的没什么两样
They could do the same thing at any Quiznos.
而且他们还会给我吐司面包呢
And they'd offer to toast it for me, too.
好吧  聪明鬼
Okay, smart guy.
我正要切除蓝斑核
I'm about to remove the locus coeruleus,
这是份超精细的工作
which is incredibly delicate work.
你来吧
Have at it.
好啊
All right.
我对这种灰白质可熟悉了
I'm no stranger to a little gray matter.
蓝斑核
Locus coeruleus.
你猜得差不多了  这确实是脑子里面的
You're getting warmer-- it is, indeed, in the brain.
希望你的手有够稳
Hope your hands are steady.
这活儿细如发丝
It's the width of a single hair.
但这不过是普通的生物学
But this is just biology,
肯定难不倒向你这样的天才
so I'm sure it's no problem for a genius like you.
那是当然  你要知道在物理学领域
It's not. I'll have you know, in the field of physics,
我们研究的粒子小到
we work with particles so small,
可以嘲笑你们的蓝斑体型过胖
they make fat jokes about the locus coeruleus.
就是说  你们家蓝斑闲坐家中
I.e., when your locus coeruleus sits around the house,
那家里简直水泄不通
it sits around the house.
紧张了吗  库珀博士
Oh... are we nervous, Dr. Cooper?
没有
No.
你所看到的
What you see
是我满怀信心的颤抖
is a man trembling with confidence.
蓝斑通常都会出这么多血吗
Does a locus coeruleus normally bleed that much?
不  但你的手指会
No. But your thumb does.
天啊
Oh, dear.
哎哟  就你还想当生物学家呢
Yeah, you're a biologist.
你来这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我在度假
I'm on vacation.
按照社会惯例
Social convention dictates
我应该来当地酒吧放松一下
that I let my hair down at a local watering hole.
社会惯例就是个屁
Social convention is stupid.
你的手指怎么了
What happened to your thumb?
我有十个手指十个脚趾
I have ten fingers and ten toes.
要我每个指头的故事你都要听
If I tell you a story about each one of them,
那可得说上一整天  所以算了吧
we'll be here all day-- let's just move on.
要点什么
What can I get you?
既然我是在度假
Ah, seeing as I'm on vacation,
凤椰朗姆酒比较合适
uh, Pina Colada seems appropriate.
凤梨片椰奶和白色褐色朗姆酒
调制成的加勒比海特色鸡尾酒
多加凤梨片和鲜奶油
Extra pineapple slices, extra whipped cream,
再给双份樱桃和小伞
extra cherries, extra umbrellas,
还有  不要朗姆酒
and, uh, hold the rum.
记得别让我喝太多
Don't let me have too many of those.
您二位在这干嘛呀
Hey, what are you guys doing here?
我们都是大人  就该在吧台这喝酒
We're grown men; we drink at bars.
扯  胡扯
No and no.
你和伯纳黛特还好吧
Everything okay with you and Bernadette?
好啊  当然好
Oh, yeah, sure.
你和艾米呢  还好吗
You and Amy? Good?
好得不能再好了
Oh, better than good.
要知道  她们都会把生活中的每件事都发短信告诉我
You know those girls text me every detail of their lives as it happens.
我是不会签婚前协议的
I'm not signing a prenup.
好吧  霍华德·沃罗威茨  给我听着
All right, Howard Wolowitz, listen up.
她给你什么你就签什么
You sign anything she puts in front of you,
因为你是世上最幸运的人
because you are the luckiest man alive.
要是失去了她
If you let her go,
你再也不可能找到像她这么好的
there is no way you can find anyone else--
我是代表全体女同胞说这话
speaking on behalf of all women,
你绝对不可能再找到  我们开会一致认同的
it is not gonna happen; we had a meeting.
还有你  一个成年人
And you, a grown man
-居然看到一点点血就晕倒  -拜托
- fainting at the sight of a little blood. - Excuse me,
这个伤口那是相当大
this is a fairly substantial wound.
你...
You...
艾米  艾米  艾米
Amy? Amy? Amy?
有何贵干
What do you want?
我希望能继续在你实验室里度假
I was kind of hoping I could continue vacationing in your laboratory.
毕竟当初我预定了一整周
After all, I did book the whole week.
你真的以为就凭你昨天那样
Do you honestly think you can just waltz back in here
还能轻易地回来这里吗
after the way you behaved yesterday?
昨天我那是身不由已
I was not myself.
因为手指失血过多
I had lost a lot of thumb blood.
这话可不算道歉
That's not an apology.
就你不觉得而已
That is your opinion.
我想听的是真正的道歉
I want a real apology.
-我很抱歉你没有能够...  -不对
- I'm sorry that you weren't able to... - No.
抱歉我的天赋...
...that my genius...
不对
No.
抱歉那肥皂太...
...that the soap was...
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
好吧
Fine.
对不起
Sorry.
我原谅你
You're forgiven.
你若真想留下来  就先去洗那些烧杯
Now, if you want to stay, get started on those beakers.
昨天就没洗干净
They're still dirty from yesterday.
明年度假我要去"未来世界"玩
Next year I'm going to EPCOT.
你在生我气吗
Are you mad at me?
不  我没有生你气
No. I'm not mad at you.
我只是...
I just...
希望你直接跟我说
wish you would have come to me,
而不是让我从某些书呆口中听到
so I didn't have to hear it through the nerd-vine.
那我们该怎么办
So, what are we gonna do?
你真的想让我签婚前协议吗
You really want me to sign a prenup?
我不知道
I don't know.
虽然我爸在这点态度上非常强硬
My dad's pretty insistent on it, though.
何不让我跟你爸谈谈  来个男人之间的对话
Why don't I talk to your dad, man-to-man?
真的吗  那太好了
Really? Oh, that'd be so great!
就这么说定了
Done.
我先警告你一些注意事项
I should probably give you a heads-up about a couple of things.
虽然我爸已经从警局退休了
Even though he's retired from the police force,
他还是配着枪
he still carries his gun.
但别担心  他不会开枪的
But don't worry, he won't shoot it.
更多是想彰显自己时髦
It's more of a fashion statement.
好的
Okay.
为安全起见  你跟他谈的时候
And just to be safe, when you talk to him,
千万别提起吉米·卡特  园艺师
don't bring up Jimmy Carter, gardeners,
外国人  同性恋者  西恩·潘
foreign people, homosexuals, Sean Penn,
第二次梵蒂冈大公会议  枪支管理法  有机食品
Vatican II, gun control, organic food,
指定打击规则  资源回收  或你是犹太人的事实
the designated hitter rule, recycling or the fact that you're Jewish.
明白  明白
Got it, got it.
把这单子电邮给我吧
Will you e-mail me that list?
所以要当心的是
So the thing to watch for,
若他冲你吼  那就没事
if he's shouting at you, you're okay,
但若他开始变得沉默
but if he starts to get real quiet,
千万别跟他目光接触  有多快就跑多块
leave as quickly as you can without making eye contact.
切勿跑直线  要之字形逃命
Not in a straight line-- throw some zigs and zigs in there.
反正这事也不是迫在眉睫
You know, this isn't that pressing.
不如等五月份我再找他谈吧
Why don't I talk to him about it in May.
五月你就上国际空间站了
In May you're gonna be on the International Space Station.
空间站也有电话的嘛
They got a phone.